A Guide to the Governor's Palace Land Papers, 1815-1904
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Governor's Palace Lands Papers, 1866-1904, 1815-1904.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 30.1
12 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1930.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1552)
Biographical/Historical Information
Official residence of the royal governor's of Virginia while the capital was in Williamsburg. Also served as the official residence for Governor's Patrick Henry and Thomas Jefferson.
Scope and Content Information
Letters, deeds, and miscellaneous legal papers regarding sale of certain parts of the land formerly attached to the Governor's Palace in Williamsburg, Va. Involved in the sales were such prominent nineteenth- century residents of Williamsburg as Robert M. Garrett, John M. Gregory, Dr. Samuel S. Griffin, Lovey T. Jackson, Robert Saunders, Samuel Shield, Robert F. N. Smith, and C. B. Upshaw and Samuel Smith McCroskey of Northampton County.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Index Terms
Persons:
Garrett, Robert M., 1808-1885.; Gregory, John M., 1804- 1888.; Griffin, Samuel Stuart, 1782-1864.; Jackson, Lovey T.; McCrosky, Samuel Smith, d. 1790.; Saunders, Robert, 1805-1869.; Shield, Samuel, Clerk.; Smith, Robert F. N.; Upshur, C. B.
Corporate Names:
Governor's Palace (Williamsburg, Va.)
Geographical Names:
Carr's Hill (Williamsburg, Va.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds--Virginia--Williamsburg--19th century.
Contents List
- Certificate of B. Upshur, Clerk, Northampton County Court, on Robert F. N. Smith's certificate as administrator of Rev. Dr. S. S. McCrosky's estate, 9 January 1815.
- Deed for Palace Lands, Robert F. N. Smith for Dr. S. S. McCrosky's estate, to Robert Saunders, 4 April 1816.
- Deed, Robert & Lucy B. Saunders to John M. Gregory, 2 pieces 20 June 1838.
- Deed, John & Amanda Gregory to S. S. Griffen, 10 July 1841.
- Extract from Saunders to Gregory deed to Palace lands 2 September 1843.
- Review of deeds to Carr's Hill, Williamsburg, prepared for Dr. Samuel S. Griffen by Samuel Shield, Clerk, 2 September 1843.
- Letter, Robert Saunders to Samuel S. Griffen, 27 September 1843.
- Extract from chain of title to Palace land, 2 pieces, ca. 1843.
- Lovey T. Jackson to Robert M. Garrett. Deed of life interest to house and lot in the city of Williamsburg bounded by the premises of Dr. Robert M. Garrett and Capital Landing Road, for $50. Receipted for payment, 9 May 1866.
- C. B. Chapman to the Peninsula Bank, Williamsburg. Deeds and transactions on the Garrett farm, 9 August 1904.